twenga.com.au 2015-12-04

# Privacy policy

Home › Privacy policy

At Twenga we recognise that privacy is important. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the products, services and websites offered by Twenga or its subsidiaries or affiliated companies; collectively, Twenga’s “services”. In addition, where more detailed information is needed to explain our privacy practices, we post supplementary privacy notices to describe how particular services process personal information.

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to [contact us](http://www.twenga.com.au/contact.php "contact us") through our website.

## Information we collect and how we use it

We offer a number of services that do not require you to register for an account or provide any personal information to us, such as a search on Twenga. In order to provide our full range of services, we may collect the following types of information:

  * ›Information you provide - When you sign up for a Twenga Account or other Twenga service or promotion that requires registration, we ask you for personal information (such as your name, email address and an account password). For certain services, such as our advertising programmes, we also request credit card or other payment account information which we maintain in encrypted form on secure servers. We may combine the information you submit under your account with information from other Twenga services or third parties in order to provide you with a better experience and to improve the quality of our services. For certain services, we may give you the opportunity to opt out of combining such information.
  * ›Cookies - When you visit Twenga, we send one or more cookies – a small file containing a string of characters – to your computer that uniquely identifies your browser. We use cookies to improve the quality of search on Twenga by storing user preferences and tracking user trends, such as how people search. 

Third party cookies may be placed on Twenga websites and disclose information about user cookie settings. In no case will these third party cookies have access to user personal data. 

  * ›Log information - When you access a search on Twenga, our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website. These server logs may include information such as your web request, Internet Protocol address, browser type, browser language, the date and time of your request and one or more cookies that may uniquely identify your browser. Also, in order to protect you from fraud, phishing, and other misconduct, we may collect information about your interaction with our services. Any such information we collect will only be used to detect and prevent fraud or other misconduct.
  * ›User communications - When you send email or other communications to Twenga, we may retain those communications in order to process your inquiries, respond to your requests and improve our services.
  * ›Affiliated sites - We offer some of our services in connection with other web sites. Personal information that you provide to those sites may be sent to Twenga in order to deliver the service. We process such information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The affiliated sites may have different privacy practices and we encourage you to read their privacy policies.
  * ›Links - Twenga may present links in a format that enables us to keep track of whether these links have been followed. We use this information to improve the quality of our search technology, customised content and advertising.
  * ›Other sites - This Privacy Policy applies to Twenga services only. We do not exercise control over the sites displayed as pages or as links from within our various services. These other sites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you.

Twenga only processes personal information for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy and/or the supplementary privacy notices for specific services. In addition to the above, such purposes include:

  * ›Providing our services to users, including the display of customised content and advertising;
  * ›Auditing, research and analysis in order to maintain, protect and improve our services;
  * ›Ensuring the technical functioning of our network; and
  * ›Developing new services.

You can find more information about how we process personal information by referring to the supplementary privacy notices for particular services.

Twenga processes personal information on our servers in the Netherlands and in other countries. In some cases, we process personal information on a server outside your own country. We may process personal information to provide our own services. In some cases, we may process personal information on behalf of and according to the instructions of a third party, such as our advertising partners.

## Choices for personal information

When you sign up for a particular service that requires registration, we ask you to provide personal information. If we use this information in a manner different than the purpose for which it was collected, then we will ask for your consent prior to such use.

If we propose to use personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the specific service privacy notices, we will offer you an effective way to opt out of the use of personal information for those other purposes. We will not collect or use sensitive information for purposes other than those described in this Privacy Policy and/or in the supplementary service privacy notices, unless we have obtained your prior consent.

Most browsers are initially set up to accept cookies, but you can reset your browser to refuse all cookies or to indicate when a cookie is being sent. However, some Twenga features and services may not function properly if your cookies are disabled.

You can decline to submit personal information to any of our services, in which case Twenga may not be able to provide those services to you.

## Information sharing

Twenga only shares personal information with other companies or individuals outside of Twenga in the following limited circumstances:

  * ›We have your consent. We require opt-in consent for the sharing of any sensitive personal information.
  * ›We provide such information to our subsidiaries, affiliated companies or other trusted businesses or persons for the purpose of processing personal information on our behalf. We require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
  * ›We have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation or disclosure of such information is reasonably necessary to (a) satisfy any applicable law, regulation, legal process or enforceable governmental request, (b) enforce applicable Terms of Service, including investigation of potential violations thereof, (c) detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security or technical issues, or (d) protect against imminent harm to the rights, property or safety of Twenga, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.

If Twenga becomes involved in a merger, acquisition, or any form of sale of some or all of its assets, we will provide notice before personal information is transferred and becomes subject to a different privacy policy. We may share with third parties certain pieces of aggregated, non-personal information, such as the number of users who searched for a particular term, for example, or how many users clicked on a particular offer. Such information does not identify you individually.

Please [contact us](http://www.twenga.com.au/contact.php "contact us") for any additional questions about the management or use of personal data.

## Information security

We take appropriate security measures to protect against unauthorised access to or unauthorised alteration, disclosure or destruction of data. These include internal reviews of our data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures, as well as physical security measures to guard against unauthorised access to systems where we store personal data.

We restrict access to personal information to Twenga employees, contractors and agents who need to know that information in order to operate, develop or improve our services. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.

## Data integrity

Twenga processes personal information only for the purposes for which it was collected and in accordance with this Privacy Policy or any applicable service-specific privacy notice. We review our data collection, storage and processing practices to ensure that we only collect, store and process the personal information needed to provide or improve our services. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the personal information we process is accurate, complete, and current, but we depend on our users to update or correct their personal information whenever necessary.

## Accessing and updating personal information

When you use Twenga services, we make good faith efforts to provide you with access to your personal information and either to correct this data if it is inaccurate or to delete such data at your request if it is not otherwise required to be retained by law or for legitimate business purposes. We ask individual users to identify themselves and the information requested to be accessed, corrected or removed before processing such requests, and we may decline to process requests that are unreasonably repetitive or systematic, require disproportionate technical effort, jeopardise the privacy of others, or would be extremely impractical (for instance, requests concerning information residing on backup tapes), or for which access is not otherwise required. In any case where we provide information access and correction, we perform this service free of charge, except if doing so would require a disproportionate effort. Some of our services have different procedures to access, correct or delete users’ personal information. We provide the details for these procedures in the specific privacy notices or FAQs for these services.

## Enforcement

Twenga regularly reviews its compliance with this Privacy Policy. Please feel free to direct any questions or concerns regarding this Privacy Policy or Twenga’s treatment of personal information by [contact us](http://www.twenga.com.au/contact.php "contact us") through this web site.

## Changes to this Privacy Policy

Please note that this Privacy Policy may change from time to time. We will not reduce your rights under this Privacy Policy without your explicit consent, and we expect most such changes will be minor. Regardless, we will post any Privacy Policy changes on this page and, if the changes are significant, we will provide a more prominent notice (including, for certain services, email notification of Privacy Policy changes). Each version of this Privacy Policy will be identified at the top of the page by its effective date.

If you have any additional questions or concerns about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to [contact us](http://www.twenga.com.au/contact.php "contact us") any time through this web site.
